All right, until others join, I hope we can
start. So good evening again, everyone. Today
you have joined the project Q&A session for
Superluminal Communication Voice Codec, which
is sponsored by Map Tech. And I'm your teaching
assistant for Rishika.
So before we discuss and move into the Q&A session,
I will give you a brief introduction on this
project and how the things work. To get an approach
to that, I would like to start from our topic,
the superluminal communication voice decoder.
This is how I codec. So this is how I decode
this project. So when it comes to superluminal
communication, if you have already gone through
the given requirement specification. So it discusses
about this as a method, a communication method,
which is faster than the light of the speed.
So superluminal communication is identified
as not physically available up to now. So to
address. this issue. Scientists have tried
different kind of methods and they have come
up with a theoretical concept called wormholes.
So wormholes, simply we can identify as a tunnel
point A to point B. So let's say it would be
the fastest method that we can move from one
point to another. Otherwise it will if we choose
the regular part it will take a longer time
but this provides us a short path in a faster
way. So now when it comes to these wormholes
There we cannot try with like starting point,
we cannot try that with trying to you know
teleport some human beings. So that's why we
are starting this ground level as we are trying
to send some information from point A to point
B and from there onwards we try to figure out
how these things can be transported from one
point to another. And creating this kind of
wormholes, it takes a lot of time, and also
it's very costly. And since it is a very small
space, some spacecraft might not pass through
it. So that's why we are moving with this information
transmission and try to. find out a way of coming
up with the solution and if we move to the
voice codec part, so in this project in this
application we are trying to encode and decode
provided audio input and moving on so simply
what you can see here is what is we are expecting
from our project. We will be creating a program
where it has two functionalities as encoding
and decoding. So as you can see here, you will
provide an input file to your program, encode
it, and it will compress your file and provide
an output. as payload and that payload again
you can the person who is in the other end can
use your program the same program that you
have written and decode that file and come up
with the output file as voice underscore out
dot vape. So after decompressing it. So I hope
you all have already participated the kickoff
So as Simon explains, this is the workflow of
your intended program. Again, you will provide
a voice.wav file as the input audio file, which
is uncompressed. And that uncompressed file
will go through your program, and it will be
encoded. payload bin will be created and if
you want to decode that you can use the same
application and decode it and have the output
dot wave file. So when it comes to measuring
how much of compression that you have done
these formulas are given. So for an example
let's say the initial file is kilobyte file
that you have input and once you try to compress
it you can create a payload file let's say
1 KB file and that file again the person who
is using the same application can decode it
and let's assume that output file is maybe 8
KB or something. So now you can see you can
calculate the compression rate over there using
this formula 1 minus size in bytes payload
bin which means this 1kb as I mentioned before
and it divided by the initial input file size
and it would be 10. So you will get the answer
as 90% or something. So likewise you can figure
out the compression rate of this whole process.
And another thing is the accuracy that we are
trying to figure out here. How are we trying
to measure the accuracy of your application?
So if you have a.
If you have a going through the. Uh, sorry.
Give me one sec.
Yeah, so when it comes to accuracy, if you have
provided the file, it's an audio file. You
can listen to that. And then at the end of the
day, once you have used your file and decoded,
then you will get the output file. And if that
audio file is also audible, I hope everyone
have participated the kickoff meeting. So over
there. like Simon's nicely explained with two
different audio examples how initial input file
sounds very natural with the human voice and
somehow at the end of the process how the recorded
file is less audible. So I hope that comparison
is does make sense to you and That's the current
accuracy that we're trying to measure with
this application. And talking about the project
aim, we try to highly efficient voice and decoder
with maximal compression and high intelligibility.
And these are the functional requirements that
provided by our client. So you are intended
to create a product which should be a name
as for these naming conventions. If you are
using a python script you can use that name
as your application name.py or if you are creating
a standalone executable you can name it as
name.exe. And this is how you should maintain
the encoding states. So your file, sorry your
application is given and in there this encoding
script will be run and then with this input.wav
file you will be creating a payload one. And
when it comes to decoding again in your program
this decoding function or script will be run
and the payload will be created and the output
sorry payload is this what you call it input
this input parameter is taken to the decode
function and then we'll create this output.wav
file and apart from that these are some additional
functional requirements that you can see here.
So they are expecting you to
script or the EXE file and this should be able
to run on a virtual machine running on Windows
on Azure. And another thing is this the.wav
file is a single channel LPCM sampled at 44.1
kHz with 16 bits and you can use the human voice
audio. somethings for this. So these are the
project deliverables. We need to provide an
encoding algorithm, and also should be able
to provide the decoding algorithm. And you need
to document these things, how these encoding
and decoding processes are working. Apart from
that, I have given you some sample user stories.
For an example, if we take the first one as
a user, I want to upload a.wav file to the
codec so that I can encode the input file. And
the acceptance criteria would be user can browse
and select a.wav file from their local file
system and an the file has invalid file type.
And another user story as you can see here is
as user I want to encode the audio file so
that I can compress the input file. So likewise
there's another one for downloading this output
file and what are the acceptance criteria. So
feel free to change these user stories as per
your requirement, but maintaining the initial
requirements from the client. And you can create
as many user stories as you want. There's no
number of user stories that you need to provide.
That depends on how your teams work. these are
some sample user stories. Feel free to change
these things and when we are moving forward
with your projects. So yeah with that I conclude
the presentation. Let's move on to the Q&A session.
Does anyone have any questions?
Hi, how are you? Thank you for the presentation.
I just have two quick questions. First is when
we're going to, because I feel like we're going
to do the first sprint planning meeting this
week. And then sprint one is going to kick off
next week. So how are we going to arrange the
very first meeting? I assume you should participate
in this? Yes. So once the groups are created,
do you have group already? Yep. Yeah so nice.
So then what you can do is you can plan a little
bit. I hope from our side we will provide you
the GitHub reports and everything and once
you have prepared it the first sprint would
be like having some discussions about the project
and you know get some plan the work ahead and
setting up the things likewise. And from our
side as a TA, I will provide you the list and
the available time slots that I have. So based
on those time slots, you can pick one and arrange
a team link with me. Sorry. team meeting and
then share that with me. So that whole time
slot will be dedicated for every upcoming meeting
that I have with you. Yes. I'm sorry, I didn't
get it. Is it like, is the time slots gonna
be released by the end of this week? Is that?
Hopefully yes. Yes, hopefully yes. Because
we cannot move forward from the next week or
not. All right, so probably the meeting is
gonna be next week.
Yes. Oh, yes. OK. That makes sense. Another
issue is I had a little bit of research of
this topic. I find it quite complicated. So
I just want to ask, is it OK to just leverage
models off the shelf? Because we got a lot of
audio compression algorithms and even machine
learning models available. Is it OK to just
to just leverage those models? Yeah, I think
in Simon's speech as well, he has no obligation
on using the existing
technologies or existing embeds. Yeah, he has
allowed that. Oh, okay. So it is fine if you
really can't just tweak some like parameters
if we just don't have the ability. So that's
fine. Is that correct? Okay. Yes. Otherwise,
you can use the existing techniques that are
available or else you can come up with your
own novel approach as well. Okay, that makes
sense. All right. Thank you so much.
Anyone else? Hey. So this is marked as an AI
question, but I'm wondering
how do we use AI in this? Or is that just completely
up to us? As a proxy client, I'm just giving
you the requirements. So how the technology
should work, which text that you are using
and how the design should be or everything comes
from your side. I'm just giving you the requirements.
Okay. All right. Anyone else?
Bill, there's a question in the chat which basically
says, when can we get started on the coding?
The course timetable says spring one starts
Monday. Yeah, there's no, as per my knowledge,
there's no limitation on that, but you might
need to have a proper plan on maintaining these
things. I think up to now, you might have to,
if you are starting coding by now, you might
need to keep it in one of your github reports.
And then once we have created a reports for
the group, you might have to transfer those
things into it. Okay, thank you.
Anyone else?
And would you mind telling me the groups that
you are currently in so that I can make some
notes on that? If you can put those group numbers
on the check, that's also fine.
This is just for my reference.
Oh, good. Okay. Thanks, everyone.
So, UG3, UG1, PG1 right? Cool. Thank you. Any
other questions you need to clarify regarding
how the course work or how the upcoming sessions
happen? Do we need to provide any sort of interface?
Or is it fine if it's all just command line?
Up to now, there's no requirement as providing
an interface for this one, just command line.
Yeah, all right.
Anything else? Hi, this is Ruxi. Can you hear
me? Yes. Yeah. Thank you. Will you upload the
slides that you showed before? The slide set?
Yeah. Yes. Anyway, upload the recording. So
from there onwards, you can go through. Oh,
yeah. Yeah. OK.
Any other questions?
Um, with the initial report...
Because do we need Spring 1 to happen before
we can start writing the initial report? Or
can we just start writing the initial report
because it is due next week? Let me check.
I just need to have a quick look. There are
some like certain factors in it that I think
might be dependent on the Spring meeting, the
first one.
at the assignment section and the date is 18th
of August it says
I think the due date is 18th August, right?
Which means... Let me... Back on the calendar...
18th of August. Yeah. Oh, you can start.
12th August onwards as per the calendar in the
home page. Okay. But the sprint planning and
these kind of discussions will happen in this
week throughout the week and if you have further
problems even after this session feel free to
join there are two sessions tomorrow and day
after and you can join those things as well.
Okay. So these sessions are potentially just
the sprint planning meetings itself? Um, we
can't exactly say this is just to clarify or
clear the space. Uh, if you have any doubts
on the projects and everything before you,
uh, get into the projects, uh, real time, we
just clarify the environment and yeah, clear
the things up. Okay. Thank you.
Oh, so for the customer Q&A part in the initial
report, we can use questions we asked here
as well, can we? Yeah, yeah, of course. OK.
Yes.
And once you create it, this is what happened
in the last year. So once you have created
the groups and you are allocated to the groups,
you might ask questions in the chat. So you
can.
get those questions as well as client clarifications
and everything. So you can use those questions
as well. It's a way that you try to clarify
about the project.
Does it make sense? Yeah.
Um...
What I meant was like, I am not providing the
links for the meetings. You have to create
the links and share that with me. Oh, okay.
So we can make our own links and share them
with you and hopefully you're available at those
times. Yeah, better to be since I think Zoom
is freely available for the university students,
right? So Zoom will be fine. if not, we can
use Teams as well. Do you have your timetable
though? I will provide after discussing with
Dr. Amali, the course coordinator. Okay, perfect.
So I'll just change that.
Hi, this is Lucy. Yeah. Yeah, I saw that in
our timetable, we have an online meeting from
this week. Do you know what this meeting is
about? Our team to arrange a kickoff meeting
or is for the lecture or anything else. It's
an online meeting. I didn't find any Zoom link.
Who has created that? I believe it's just a
block off in everyone's calendar. to make sure
that we pay time towards the groups because
um Amali was also saying the same thing that
there's um even the lecture times can be used
to actually just work on the project itself.
Okay so it's all for the project we can arrange
for ours on our schedule yeah. Yes memories.
And also, does this project provide us some
twice algorithm that can be used? Or it all
depends on our choices? From the client side?
Yeah, from the client side. Yeah, I hope I
understood what you're asking. So from the client
side, we didn't get any coding part or any.
halfway done application. So it's you to figure
out how you're gonna do this. What is the script
or the EXE that either one of them you can use
and start working on it. Yeah, so it's not
also about the project management, it's also
about coding, or any other algorithm that all
depends on us. But let me clarify it a little
bit. So this project will provided by our client
Maptic. You might have heard there's a competition
and everything happening from there. But for
the SEP module, we need to maintain this. Now,
we try to create a real working environment
here. by giving you the real project. And we
try to employ the agile methodologies like
scrum practice to your teams and working on
scrum sprint-wise. And with that, we try to
make you practice about how we can utilize this
scrum and how are we gonna use. the sprint,
how we're going to manage the sprint work and
everything, and what are these scrum events
and everything. We just try to give you some
hands-on experience on that. So yeah. OK, thank
you.
Any other questions?
should we email the links to you? You mean the
meeting links? Yes. Yeah you can email them
to me otherwise I hope by the end of this week
we will be creating the groups as well in teams.
Yeah perfect. So you can share the links through
the teams as well but make sure if it is a
recurring one that's Perfect. But if you are
like generating new links, yeah, new, new links,
then make sure you are, you're not waiting until
the last minute. That's a request. Yeah, no,
obviously. Um, just one more question about
that. Um, we were told in the lectures that
the sprint planning and the sprint retrospective
would potentially be a say in the same meeting,
so there would just be one meeting itself. That
wouldn't be the case for the first one. So
we would still have two meetings and then the
sprint two planning and sprint one retrospective
will be together. For the first one, I hope.
Since we have no previous sprint to retrospect
that. So we will go with the planning session
only. Okay. And from the second week or the
second sprint onward. We will be having both
sessions together. Like I think 25 minutes.
Just in the same time, 25 minutes. Yes, 25 minutes
per group. So you will be walk me through,
yeah, you can walk me through the, your backlog
and what you have done. Those things will be
discussed in those mini meetings. And you will
be providing us with the product. backlog correct?
Yes, last time that was the case. I have to
talk with Dr. Amali on that. Okay, no worries.
But meanwhile, feel free to create your own
user stories and you know, have a like try
to create a backlog other than waiting for the
last minute. Just with what you have identified,
you can start from that. Okay cool.
Any other questions?
Yeah, so if you have further questions, feel
free to join next two sessions as well. And
if you need any other clarification regarding
the course or how the things are going to work,
you can drop an email to me. You can find my
email on the homepage. Or else you can directly...
contact Dr. Amali on course regarding things.
Thank you. All right. I hope.
Everyone has asked their questions and clarified
the things.
Yeah, all right then. Yeah. OK, thanks everyone
for joining. Hope you have to see you on upcoming
sessions. Yeah. Have a good one. Bye, see you.
OK.